{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shuka","incorrectAnswers":["Kaftan","Thobe","Dashiki"],"question":"Which of these is a style of cloth used to make clothing by the Maasai people of East Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"23","incorrectAnswers":["10","160","12"],"question":"How many pairs of chromosomes does the average person have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isosceles triangle","incorrectAnswers":["Equilateral triangle","Scalene triangle","Rectangle"],"question":"What is the name of a triangle with two sides of equal length?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cameron Diaz","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kristin Scott Thomas","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has played major roles in films including Gangs of New York and The Mask?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Nicole Kidman","Natalie Portman"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including The Deer Hunter and Out of Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Barba non facit philosophum","incorrectAnswers":["Ad victoriam philos","Una philos non facit ver","Philosophum ad meliora"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'A beard doesn't make one a philosopher'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Royal disease","incorrectAnswers":["Laughing disease","Deadly disease","Happy disease"],"question":"As what is haemophilia also known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Slovakia","Czech Republic","Hungary"],"question":"Warsaw is the capital of what country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ghosting","incorrectAnswers":["Dropping","Vanishing","Negging"],"question":"In modern slang, what is the term for abruptly cutting off all communication, especially with a romantic partner?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I am Groot.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\"","\"The stuff that dreams are made of.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Clint Eastwood","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Lee","James Dean","Marlon Brando"],"question":"Which actor starred in The Good, the Bad and the Ugly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry II","incorrectAnswers":["Henry IV","Richard II","Richard I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1154-1189?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"During WWII a Jewish waiter uses humor to protect his son from the realities of war.","incorrectAnswers":["Eddy has a week to pay back £500,000 after losing a poker game to a powerful local mobster.","The life of the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule.","A secretly ruthless woman insinuates herself into the lives of an aging actor and her circle of theater friends."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Life Is Beautiful?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A law enforcement agent pursues four replicants who have returned to Earth to find their creator.","incorrectAnswers":["A man houses over a thousand Tutsi refugees during their struggle against the Hutu militia.","When a serial killer murders key political figures, a vigilante is forced to intervene.","An insurance representative lets a housewife seduce him into a scheme of insurance fraud and murder."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Blade Runner?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Collage","incorrectAnswers":["Watercolor","Sculpture","Pointilism"],"question":"What is the word for a composition made of cut and pasted pieces of materials?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Defoe","Percy Bysshe Shelley","Walter Scott"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Opticks, or a Treatise of the Reflections, Refractions, Inflections and Colours of Light'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anthony Eden","incorrectAnswers":["Clement Atlee","Margaret Thatcher","Tony Daniels"],"question":"Who succeeded Winston Churchill when he resigned in 1955?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Estonia","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Macedonia","Bolivia"],"question":"In which country is vana tallinn a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sputnik","incorrectAnswers":["Endeavour","Landsat","Terra"],"question":"What was the name of the first artificial satellite to be launched into space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Salvador Dali","incorrectAnswers":["Pablo Picasso","Andy Warhol","Damien Hirst"],"question":"Which artist produced a lobster telephone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is linguine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chocolate ","incorrectAnswers":["Fudge","Cheese","Cream"],"question":"What Is Usually Served With A Fruit Fondue?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"England","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Thailand","Mexico"],"question":"In which country is gin a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["ABBA","The Allman Brothers Band","Oasis"],"question":"Robin Gibb is one of the brothers who formed which band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"M","incorrectAnswers":["Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery","Apocalypse Now","Home Alone"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Hans Beckert'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Moorish","incorrectAnswers":["Byzantine","Neoclassical","Gothic"],"question":"Which of the following is a style of Islamic architecture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Black Widow","incorrectAnswers":["Brown Recluse","Daddy Longlegs","Tarantula"],"question":"Which venomous spider is recognized by its hourglass-shaped mark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"23","incorrectAnswers":["10","2","12"],"question":"How Many Pairs of Chromosomes Does The Average Human Have?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I'll have what she's having.\"","\"I love lamp.\"","\"Snap out of it!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Psycho'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"PETA","incorrectAnswers":["WWF","Greenpeace","The Humane Society"],"question":"What animal rights organization is known for its campaigns against animal testing and meat eating?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mother","incorrectAnswers":["HAL","Colossus","Jarvis"],"question":"What is the nickname of the ship's computer in the 1979 film Alien?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'My Generation'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The heart","incorrectAnswers":["Knots","Japanese people","Poker"],"question":"What is Cardiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Flaubert","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Salammbô'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Timothy Spall","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Newman","Tobey Maguire","Dennis Hopper"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The King's Speech and Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pearl Harbour","incorrectAnswers":["D Day","The bombing of hiroshima","The Nazi invasion of France"],"question":"Which military attack took place on Dec. 7, 1941?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I Am Not A Lawyer","incorrectAnswers":["I'm Anal","I Also Now Am Lonely","I'm Attractive, Not A Loser"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'IANAL' mean?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia ","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Europe","Africa"],"question":"Which Of The Worlds Continents Has The Highest Population?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln","incorrectAnswers":["George Washington","John F Kennedy","John Quincy Adams"],"question":"What United States president was in office during the civil war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Insomnia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Denmark","Switzerland"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kingdom of the Netherlands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Maurice Gibb","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Jones","Paul McCartney","Brian Wilson"],"question":"Who did the singer Lulu marry in 1969?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"\"Annie\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"The Lion King\"","\"Phantom of the Opera\"","\"Les Miserables\""],"question":"What is the name of the ever-popular musical that features songs such as \"Little Girls\" and \"You Won't Be an Orphan for Long\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luanda","incorrectAnswers":["Brazzaville","Nairobi","Dakar"],"question":"What is the capital of Angola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Go","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Chess","Clue"],"question":"What is the name of the classic game where players take turns placing black and white stones in an attempt to capture areas of the board?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Black Thursday","incorrectAnswers":["Dark Wednesday","Sorrowful Sunday","Miserable Monday"],"question":"How is the stockmarket collapse of the 24th October 1929 better known?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"South Korea & Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","South Africa","France"],"question":"Which country hosted the 2002 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Israel","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Portugal","Chile"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'White with a blue star centered between two equal horizontal blue bands'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sir Francis Drake","incorrectAnswers":["Horatio Nelson","George Rodney","John Jervis"],"question":"Who Played Bowls Before Engaging The Spanish Armada?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"rocks and the conditions by which they form","incorrectAnswers":["demons","medicine relating to women, or of women in general","prehistoric metaphytes "],"question":"What is Petrology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aphrodisiacs","incorrectAnswers":["Elixirs","Potions","Tonics"],"question":"Named after a Greek love goddess, which word is used for items that stimulate sexual desire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bugatti","incorrectAnswers":["Honda","Ferrari","Chevrolet"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Veyron?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Serbia","Senegal","Singapore"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.se' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hotel Rwanda","incorrectAnswers":["The Terminator","Psycho","City of God"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A man houses over a thousand Tutsi refugees during their struggle against the Hutu militia.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Baku","incorrectAnswers":["Palikir","Valletta","Monrovia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Azerbaijan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joker","incorrectAnswers":["1917","Mad Max: Fury Road","Grave of the Fireflies"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Apartheid","incorrectAnswers":["Apathy","Caste system","Feudalism"],"question":"What was the name of the system that kept Black and White people separated in South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Al dente ","incorrectAnswers":["Tartilli","Forte Benne","Parpa Delle"],"question":"Which Italian phrase is used to describe pasta cooked only until it offers a slight resistance when bitten?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Dead Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Mediterranean Sea","The Philippine Sea","The South China Sea"],"question":"What is the saltiest sea in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tripoli","incorrectAnswers":["Benghazi","Tehran","Rabat"],"question":"What is the capital of Libya? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Rowing","Track and field","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Mia Hamm associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Johannesburg","incorrectAnswers":["Pretoria","Cape Town","Durban"],"question":"Which city is the most populated in South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Spacey","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Richard Farnsworth","Sean Penn"],"question":"Who won the 1999 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Lester Burnham in American Beauty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Dadaism","Primitivism","post-impressionism"],"question":"The painting \"The Tower of Babel\" by Pieter Bruegel the Elder is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Precocious","incorrectAnswers":["Prodigious","Intelligent","Miraculous"],"question":"Which word is used to describe early achievement in children?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Taoism","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Zoroastrianism","Hinduism"],"question":"What religion was founded by Lao-tzu ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["New York","Florida"," Oklahoma"],"question":"In which US state did the \"Night Stalker\" serial killer commit his crime spree?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hilfiger","incorrectAnswers":["Lauren","Kors","Calvin"],"question":"What is the last name of the designer whose website is usa.tommy.com?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sparta","incorrectAnswers":["Corinth","Mystras","Thebes"],"question":"Which Greek city-state, led by Lysander, defeated Athens in 404 B.C. and established the government of the 30 tyrants over it?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Croatia","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders San Marino?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"12 Years a Slave","incorrectAnswers":["American Hustle","Captain Phillips","Dallas Buyers Club"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2013?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eight","incorrectAnswers":["Five","White","Seven"],"question":"What does the word 'ocho' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Arak","incorrectAnswers":["Sombai","Soju","Riga Black Balsam"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Jordan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Cambodia","Scandinavia"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Kibbeh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The lives of guards on Death Row are affected by a man accused of child murder and rape.","incorrectAnswers":["An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.","Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold.","After a mathematician accepts secret work in cryptography, his life takes a turn for the nightmarish."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Green Mile?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laurence Fishburne","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Gary Oldman","Donald Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Matrix and Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brideshead Revisited","incorrectAnswers":["Breakfast at Tiffany's","The Age of Innocence","An American Tragedy"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Sebastian Flyte'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bamako","incorrectAnswers":["Dakar","Accra","Kumasi"],"question":"What is the capital of Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Immigrant Song\" by Led Zeppelin","\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"When I was a young boy / My father took me into the city...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Farewell to Arms","incorrectAnswers":["The Sun Also Rises","For Whom the Bell Tolls","The Old Man and the Sea"],"question":"Which Ernest Hemingway novel features Frederic Henry, a hero who serves as an ambulance driver during World War I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Fipple","incorrectAnswers":["Smicker","Bibble","Firman"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'the mouthpiece of a recorder or similar wind instrument'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Nauru is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amélie","incorrectAnswers":["Raging Bull","The Matrix","Warrior"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A girl with her own sense of justice decides to help those around her and discovers love.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Moscow","incorrectAnswers":["St Petersburg","Kazan","Vladivostok"],"question":"What is the capital city of Russia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","South Korea","Vietnam"],"question":"Tokyo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["Sandro Botticelli","Peter Paul Rubens","Jacques-Louis David"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Les Demoiselles d’Avignon\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Table tennis","Ice Hockey","Baseball"],"question":"With which sport is Jose Mourinho associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Walter Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","J. R. R. Tolkien","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Heart of Midlothian'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crust","incorrectAnswers":["Mantle","Core","Stoam"],"question":"What is the name of the solid outermost layer of the Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Black","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Hugh Jackman","Brian Cox"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including King Kong and Enemy of the State?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X-Men: Apocalypse?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Metallica","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which band did Maurice Gibb belong to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptune","incorrectAnswers":["Uranus","Venus","Saturn"],"question":"Which planet is third in mass and eighth from the sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Hanks","incorrectAnswers":["Morgan Freeman","Nigel Hawthorne","Paul Newman"],"question":"Who won the 1994 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Forrest Gump in Forrest Gump?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Little holes","incorrectAnswers":["Small thimbles","homemade","Corkscrews"],"question":"The pasta bucatini has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A janitor has a gift for mathematics.","incorrectAnswers":["A tramp who has fallen in love with a blind flower girl saves money to help her medically.","After two male musicians witness a murder, they flee in an all-female band disguised as women.","Born in the stable next door to Christ, a man spends his life being mistaken for a messiah."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Good Will Hunting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["China","Italy","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the Sydney Opera House?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sydney Harbour Bridge ","incorrectAnswers":["The Golden Gate Bridge","Tower Bridge","Brooklyn Bridge"],"question":"Which Famous City Bridge Is Known Locally As The Coathanger?","difficulty":"hard"},